James Everett Perdue Papers
State University of New York at Oswego
- SUNY Oswego newspaper clippings, 1967 - 1970 (Box-folder 3-5)
  SUNY Oswego newspaper clippings Newspaper clippings are dated 1967 - 1970 & n.d. "SUCO President and Statesingers Coming Here for Special Program Saturday", Oswego Valley News, February, 1967. 2 copies with 2 postcards of the First Methodist Church of Fulton attached. "The Harsh Options in Quelling Riots", The Palladium-Times, May, 1970. Letter to the Editor, The Palladium Times, May, 1970 from Vivian R. Pyke. "Letter to the Editor from Lawrence Ulstein. n.d. Statement from George E. Pitluga, Professor of Astronomy. "Committee To Promote Better Climate Urged". n.d.
- SUNY Fredonia newspaper clippings, 1970 (Box-folder 3-6)
  SUNY Fredonia newspaper clippings Three newspaper clippings pertain to SUNY Fredonia. "Group Of Fredonia SUNY Students Presents Demands" by Philip J. McGan. Evening Observer, March, 1970. "College Council Approves Three Motions On Social Regulations", n.d. "Orderly Sit-in; Teacher Claims He's Out, College Class Conducted In Hallway Outside Of President Lanford's Office" by Philip J. McGan, n.d.
- SUNY Buffalo-newspapers & clippings, 1969 - 1970 (Box-folder 3-7)
  SUNY Buffalo-newspapers & clippings Two complete issues and one excerpt of UB Alumni News, 1960 & 1970 concerning student unrest. Buffalo Evening News clippings: "UB Council Issues Positions Paper on Unrest: Vows Decisive Action to Keep Campus Peace". "Bennis Quits UB Post; Student-Faculty Sessions Oppose Police Presence" "Bennis Letter Claims 3 Administration Errors" "Judge Tells UB To Show Cause In Suspensions" "Fredonia State Rejects Bid For More Student Power" by Agnes Palazzetti, March, 1970. "State U Body To Air UB Crisis", Courier Express, March, 1970. This section of the newspaper includes numerous articles under the aforementioned banner.
- Stanford University newspapers & clippings, 1970 (Box-folder 3-8)
  Three issues of The Stanford Observer are included, December 1969, May 1970 & June 1970, published by Stanford University, Stanford, California, concerning student unrest, etc. Stanford Observer excerpt, June, 1970, letter from A. L. Inderbitzen with a response from Stanford President K. S. Pitzer. Tribune Editorial Page, June 1970 article, "Stanford's Pitzer Resigns". "Pitzer Quits As President Of Stanford, Blames War, Disruptions in Decision", n.d.
- Reports, April, 1970 - June, 1970 (Box-folder 3-9)
  Reports include: President's Committee on the Nature and Basic Characteristics of the University. April 28, 1970. Interim Report. 3 typed pp. 2 copies. The President's Committee on Undergraduate Education. An Interim Report, June, 1970. 7 typed pp. Includes: The study included seven sub-committees with specific focus: Expanding educational opportunity Interdepartmental opportunities Research The curriculum The Bachelor of General Studies degree The Bachelor of Arts degree The Bachelor of Science degree Sections of report -- Rocommendations The Freshman Year The Sophomore and Junior Years The Senior Year Submitted and signed, John W. Walcott, Recorder. June 17, 1970. Graduate Committee Minutes. April 23, 1970. re: The Study of Education at Oswego. 1 page. Graduate Committee Minutes. June 4, 1970. re: The Study of Education at Oswego (SOE) Graduate Committee Commentary. June 5, 1970. re: The Study of Education at Oswego. Memo from Lou DeRitter, For the Committee on Instructional Programs to: Dr. Paul Briand, Editor, President's Study of Education at Oswego re: 1970 Interim Report. 2 pp. photocopy. Memo to Steering Committee; Study on Education Committee Subject: Preliminary Report, The President's Committee on Overseas Campuses. April 28, 1970. Signed Robert Steinen, Committee Member. 2 pp. photocopy. May Report of the Admissions and Financial Aids Committee. 6 typed pp. The President's Committee on Counseling, Academic Advisement and Placement (CAP) memo. April 28, 1970. 2 typed pp. photocopy. Students and the Extra-Curriculum by Sally J. Rist. 5 typed pp. copy. Table of Contents page to "Women's Education Committee: Interim Report". Includes: Introduction General Philosophy of Committee Function Status of Women Faculty Comments Concerning the Student Questionnaires Ratio of Women to Men on Staff at Different Ranks Sex Ratio on Academic Faculty Analysis of Staff Members by Sex Observations Concerning Current Status of Women Faculyt by Division and Department Women in Administration Status of Women Students Admissions Policy Report from Infirmary Special Regulations Placement of Women Graduates The Earnings Gap Library Holdings Concerning Women Tentative Recommendations Annotated Bibliography Plans for Fall Submitted by Dorothy Rogers, Chairman. Carl Davis, Joanne Fischetti, Barbara Gerber, Fran Janus, Patricia Peterson, Marilyn Smiley. Interim Report of the Calendar Committee. 5 pp. copy. Provisional Weather Commentary to the College Physical Environmental Committee by Robert B. Sykes, Jr., Director, LOTEL. Submitted 1 May 1970. 18 typed pp. Copy is a little faded, portions can be hard to read. Report on Pollution Subcommittee of President's Committee on the Campus Environment. 6-page report plus 3 memos. copies. Subcommittee members: Rose Fehr, American Studies Major, Senior; John Judd, LOTEL; George Maxwell, Biology; Paul Moskowitz, Biology Major, Junior; Paula Stobnicke, Biology Major, Senior. Student Report on Library Evaluation. 1 page. copy. Memo. From: President's Library Committee To: Steering Committee re: Preliminary Report of Activities. May 1, 1970. 2 typed pp. Copy is faded, difficult to read. Memo to Dr. Paul Briand From: Robert Canfield April 27, 1970 re: Progress Report, Committee on Scholarly Activities (formerly the Research Committee); Study of Education. 1 typed page. President's Committee, Faculty and Other Teaching Personnel Preliminary Report. May 4, 1970. 2 typed pp., faded text. Teaching Activity 2-page typed report. Copy is faded. Attached is article, "Statement on Faculty Workload". Excerpt from AAUW Bulletin. n.d. 3-page copy is very faded, difficult to read. Report of Committee XVI: Administrative Structure of the University. May 1, 1970. 2-page typed report. Warren E. Steinkraus, Chairman. David Pelland, Secretary. Study of Eduation at Oswego. May 1970. Memo to: Dr. J.S. Dunham from: H. Garber, Chairman re: Tentative recommendations of committee on Institutionalizing Educational Review and Innovation, Committee #17. 3 typed pp. Interim Report of the Committee on Community Affairs, Study of Education, State University College at Oswego. 4 typed pp. Submitted by Louis W. Herborg, Chairman. Preliminary report of the President's Committee on Black Studies. May 1, 1970. 2 typed pp. Respectfully submitted by David J. Winslow, chairman.
- Transcripts of Faculty Discussion Groups, April 15, 1970 - June 15, 1970 (Box-folder 3-10)
  Transcripts of Faculty Discussion Groups Includes: Minutes of Discussion Group I, Faculty Meeting, June 4, 1970. 2 typed pp. copy. Minutes of Discussion Group II (Room 102L, June 3, 1970) Moderator: Professor L. Koenigsberg Recorder: Mr. Henry B. Angle 3 typed pp. copy. Report of Discussion Group III. 4 typed pp. copy. Report of Discussion Group IV. June 15, 1970. 4 pp. copy. Memo. to: The Conference Committee from: Thomas R. Jensen, Moderator of Group VI. June 8, 1970. 3 typed pp. copy. Report of Discussion Group VII Moderator: H. Nash Recorder: R. Hubbard June 15, 1970. 4 typed pp. copy. Memo. June 5, 1970 to: Dean Wheeler and Members of Group VIII from: Fred Fischer, Moderator. Phil Downum, Recorder re: Report of the June 3rd Meeting of Group VIII in 102a Lanigan 3 typed pp. copy. Report of Discussion Group IX June 3, 1970. 2 typed pp. copy. Report of Discussion Group X June 8, 1970. 1 typed page. copy. James Soluri, Chairman Donald R. Mathieu, Recorder. Report of Discussion Group XI June 3, 1970. 2 typed pp. copy. Group XI Discussion Group. 1 page. 3 questions. n.d. Report of Subcommittee IV on Minorities of the President's Summer Conference Committee. 5 typed pp. n.d. Report of Sub-Committee IV on Minorities of the President's Summer Conference Committee. 6 typed pp., carbon copy. William B. George, Chairman. Judy Paratore, Sally Rist. Report of Sub-Committee IV on Minorities of the President's Summer Conference Committee. 6 typed pp. copy. William B. George, Chairman. Judy Paratore, Sally Rist. Correspondence to Mr. James E. Perdue from William R. Valentine, Regional Director, Office for Civil Rights, Department of Health, Education and Welfare, New York, New York. 3 pp., copy April 15, 1970.
- Reports, 1970 - 1977 (Box-folder 3-11)
  Reports. Includes: Abstract: Group V for June 3, 1970 - Discussion Pitluga, Chairman. June 16, 1970. 6 typed pp. Results of Faculty Opinionnaire re the Strike July 6, 1970. 3 typed pp. copy The Conference Committee. Handwritten note - July 8, 1970. 3 typed pp. copy. The College Community. August 5, 1970. Signed James E. Perdue, President. 2 typed pp. Sub-Committee on the College Community and Political Action. Report to President's Conference Committee. August 5, 1970. 7 typed pp. Memorandum. to: President James Perdue and the Summer Conference Committee from: Joe Orcutt August 5, 1970 Subject: Necessity for legitimizing student voices 2 typed pp. Summer Conference Committee Subcommittee on Communication -- Interim Report -- August 12, 1970 Subcommittee Members: Joseph Hecht, Richard Hyse, Roger McLaughlin, Linda Syrell, Paul Wagner. 5 typed pp. with two attachments. Memo to: Members of the Conference Committee from: H. Van Schaack re: Proposed Statement on Drugs August 14, 1970. 1 typed page Minutes, Sub-Committee on the College Community and Political Action. July 12, 1970 Present: Joe Orcutt, Peter Hertz, Fred Bartle Absent: George Pitluga. 3 typed pp. copy August 21, 1970 Memo: Conference Committee From: Fred Bartle Subject: Additional Comments to Report of Sub-Committee on the College Community and Political Action. 3 typed pp. copy Why is Oswego? College and Community, Character and Commitment.. A Self-Study of Education at Oswego College of Arts and Sciences, State University of New York. Edited by Paul L. Briand, Jr. Progress Report. August 4, 1970. 38 typed pp. copy. Whys is Oswego? College and Community, Character and Commitment. A Self-Study of Education at Oswego College of Arts and Science, State University of New York. Edited by Paul L. Briand, Jr. Progress Report. September 1970. Newspaper version. 8 pp. Freedom and Responsibility on Campus. 48 typed pp. copy Freedom and Responsibility on Campus. Final Report of the Summer Conference Committee. Edited by Paul L. Briand, Jr. Autumn 1970 72-page published version. Minority Groups Visited. High Schools Visted by Mr. Brown, 1969-1970 and Mr. Powell, Spring of 1969. 2 typed pp. copy Procedures as Adopted to be Employed by the Natural and Mathematical Sciences Division Promotion and Merit Committee (1975). 2 typed pp. copy. Final Report of the Division of Professional Studies Reorganization and Planning Committee. May 26, 1977. 31 pp.
- Framed portrait, n.d.
  Framed portrait of Dr. James Perdue. Gold frame 21" x 17". Linen matt with gold trim. Linen is soiled. Black & white photograph. 14" x 10.5" View of campus behind Dr. Perdue. The framed portrait was transferred to the college archives from University Development after being removed from Sheldon Hall.